<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Sreeraag Mohan | Personal Webpage</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2018-08-19T21:57:59+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Sreeraag Mohan</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title></title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/19/2017-07-30-the-new-arabs/"/>
   <updated>2018-08-19T21:57:59+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/19/2017-07-30-the-new-arabs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have made this revolution. Our families were used to keeping quiet. We didn’t keep quiet. We went out to get our dream.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 17 December 2010, Mohamed Bouazizi set himself on fire after a long tryst with frustration and hopelessness - frustrated at being extorted indiscriminately, hopelessness with the bleak future that greeted him in an oppressed regime that was run akin to a cartel and denied basic human rights to many. His martyrdom brought to the surface the dormant resentment among the Arab population, leading to a revolutionary wave across the Arab World. But unlike the many revolutions that had preceded it, this wave was different. For the first time, the world witnessed how intransigent regimes can be toppled by leaderless democratic crowds, brought together by social media, that stand firm and courageously refuse to go home until their demands for change are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juan Cole, noted American academic and commentator on Middle East and South Asian politics, keenly examines the causes and the characters behind these uprisings. Cole focuses on three countries in particular: Tunisia, Egypt and Libya, presenting an outstanding report on the changes these effected. Cole also presents a myriad of characters, which at times makes for complex reading, but each one of them have their unique story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Cole himself acknowledges that the revolution is far from over, the author, in his concluding statements, notes that the ideals that arose from the streets of Tunis and Tahrir Square have influenced protests and revolutions across the world; there will never be another republican monarchy in the Arab World, the millennials have brought about enough change to ensure that does not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Angel of History</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/11/21/the-angel-of-history/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/11/21/the-angel-of-history</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can’t kill desire. You can suppress it for a while, sometimes a long, long while, but one’s longings are eternal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the events of a night unfold, Rabih Alameddine paints the picture of a brilliant mind in crisis. Tormented by his past, Jacob is visited by the alluring Satan, who urges Jacob to relive his past and every painful memory, cold, hurtful Death, who taunts him to give up on his life, and the fourteen holy helpers. Alameddine, after &lt;em&gt;An Unnecessary Woman&lt;/em&gt;, amazes the reader with a profound, philosophical story that is witty, charming, and gloomy, all at the same time; a story of the war between memory and oblivion that we have to deal with in our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; How many rains must fall before the stains are washed clean once more? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacob is a gay Arab with a traumatic past living in San Francisco at the height of AIDS. Left alone after the demise of his partner, Alameddine weaves through the poet’s trauma, his naked yearning, sadness, despair and man’s utter helplessness in crisis. His struggles with remembering his partner, his yearning to forget the past, all make him drown deeper into a muddled abyss, tormented by Satan’s and Death’s misdeeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alameddine amazes the reader yet again with brilliant prose, though I feel that this book might be more challenging to get through, in comparison to &lt;em&gt;An Unnecessary Woman.&lt;/em&gt; The ramblings of a man who has lost his sanity is not something everyone can read, leave alone comprehend. But, as Satan says, &lt;em&gt;sanity is overrated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Artemis</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/11/18/artemis/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/11/18/artemis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had read &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; previously, and I started off this book with high expectations. Andy Weir’s previous book told the story of a man on Mars and was filled to the brim with brilliant science, and I expected more of the same from &lt;em&gt;Artemis&lt;/em&gt;. Turns out that this book gets there, but not quite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artemis&lt;/em&gt; is set on the moon, at the first city built on it. Weir delves into more scientific detail than &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt;, and Weir lays out a detailed description on how life would be on the moon. Weir’s research here is astounding and showcases the level of research that has gone into the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weir was never someone to claim that he is a prolific author, and that reflects here. &lt;em&gt;Artemis&lt;/em&gt; features much of the flat prose with a more-than-necessary garnishing of profanity. But what really brings down the book is its recycled plot; the plot is only half as interesting as the setting of the novel, eventually leading to its downfall towards the climax of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brownie points for the scientific insight, but well, &lt;em&gt;meh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Miss Laila - Armed and Dangerous</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/10/11/miss-laila/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/10/11/miss-laila</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;THERE ARE FACES only an Indian can make. Like that baffled face when he is shocked by the most rational outcome of his own actions. He crosses the road like a cow, and he is startled by a truck. A vehicle on the road? How? He walks across the railway track, and he finds a train hurtling towards him. A train on a railway track? He is stunned. Cops who do not wear bulletproof vests break into a house to fight militants, and they are shot in their paunches. They stagger out looking bewildered. That baffled face, when boys fall off trains because they were dangling from the doorways, when illegal homes built on infirm soil collapse, when pilgrims are squashed in annual stampedes inside narrow temples.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A drastic departure from Manu Joseph’s previous books, &lt;em&gt;Miss Laila, Armed and Dangerous&lt;/em&gt; may not seem as fiction to many. With a few cosmetic changes, this short, quick read brings the journalist in Manu Joseph back to the fore. The author spares nobody with the pen that transforms into a shotgun in his hand, and deftly strikes down the inflated ego of many. Biased as it may seem, the book displays what the author thinks about a case that shook India’s conscience, and continues to emit aftershocks even today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe as a fellow Malayalee, I too must have felt the same about Miss Laila and the minor god that is Damodarbhai. It would be terribly unfair to the author to compare this book to his previous works, as &lt;em&gt;Miss Laila, Armed and Dangerous&lt;/em&gt; stands in a league of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Unbearable Lightness of Being</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/10/02/unbearable-lightness/"/>
   <updated>2017-10-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/10/02/unbearable-lightness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who are looking for an intricate plot with definitive character development, look away, as this book is not for you. &lt;em&gt;The Unbearable Lightness of Being&lt;/em&gt; oozes Milan Kundera’s philosophy on life, and is a wonderful read, if you can keep pace with the author’s fragmented train of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leafing through this book, I found myself reaching out over and over for my highlighter. Kundera, armed with beautiful prose, often feels like a prophet, dishing out words of wisdom as the reader flips through the pages. I often felt that a critical analysis of the book, akin to one by Gurcharan Das on &lt;em&gt;The Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt; would not be a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world essentially rests on the moral perversity of the nonexistence of return. For in this world, everything is pardoned in advance, and therefore everything is cynically permitted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kundera uses the example of Hitler and the nonexistence of a second Reign of Terror in France as ways to justify the protagonist’s dilemma and his search for love with Tereza. For when it comes to questions of the heart, there is no way to test the outcome as there is no basis for comparison. Kundera states that we, as humans, live everything as it comes, and asks an important question : for what can life be worth if the first rehearsal for life is life itself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Einmal est keinmal, Franz thought to himself. What happens but once, goes the German adage, might as well not happened at all. If we have only one life to live, we might not have lived it at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making love with a woman and sleeping with a woman are two different passions, not merely different but opposite. Love does not make itself felt in the desire for copulation (a desire that extends to an infinite number of women) but in the desire for shared sleep (a desire limited to one woman).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomas, the protagonist of the story, has a serious problem with infidelity, and this is where Tomas’ dilemma stems from. But soon, Tomas does realize that his infidelities will never result in his deliverance, as is revealed from the above quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are things that can be accomplished only by violence. Physical love is unthinkable without violence.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An often misunderstood quote, Kundera here does not refer to violence as the malicious intent of one person to cause another harm. Rather, it is the emotional barriers to love that get broken down when we fall hopelessly in love with our counterpart. This is the reason love is so hard, it is the singular emotion that requires every other emotion to become present before we recognize for what it is, love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love is the longing for the half of ourselves that we have lost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The character of Tereza is Kundera’s gateway to the dichotomy of the body and the soul. Kundera pairs the body with lightness, and the soul with weight. Tomas’s infidelities weigh heavy on Tereza’s soul, so much that she is able to reconcile with the lightness. Tereza is weighed down by the events of her traumatic childhood and the issues that she thinks she has with her body. Soon after the death of their pet, Karenin, Tereza realizes that she is alone in the world, and she was nothing but a &lt;em&gt;‘rumbling of the stomach.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vertigo is something other than the fear of falling. It is the voice of emptiness below us which tempts and lures us, it is the desire to fall, against which, terrified, we defend ourselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A masterpiece of a book by Milan Kundera. One to definitely have in every avid reader’s bookshelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Difficulty of Being Good</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/07/27/the-difficulty-of-being-good/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/07/27/the-difficulty-of-being-good</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt; has always been different from other epics. It does not have a grand climax, it’s characters cannot be neatly compartmentalized, it conflicts with it’s own self multiple times. This grandiose paradox is probably what makes the &lt;em&gt;Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt; sit a notch higher than other ancient mythologies, for the epic was never about a particular hero or great achievements. The &lt;em&gt;Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt; is a treatise on &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;, and Gurcharan Das, in his book titled &lt;em&gt;The Difficulty of Being Good&lt;/em&gt;, tries to bring out parallels between episodes from the &lt;em&gt;Mahabharata&lt;/em&gt; and the contemporary world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He largely succeeds in his endeavor, with his interpretations of the carefully selected passages from the Mahabharata both deeply insightful and elevating on a philosophical level. Das is true in echoing my sentiment when he states that &lt;em&gt;‘it (the Mahabharata) poses more questions than it answers’&lt;/em&gt;, and like &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt;, in subtlety lie the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Little Life</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/07/22/a-little-life/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/07/22/a-little-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems impossible to give this gem of a book a rating anything less than five stars. Hanya Yanagihara’s &lt;em&gt;A Little Life&lt;/em&gt; is a far cry from the mundane, off the shelf books that you might pounce upon; it is a microcosm of the banality of human life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this 720-page novel, you will come across moments of joy, happiness, elation, sorrow, despair, and sheer helplessness, as the author, through her beautiful, elegant prose, masterfully manages to make the reader relate to the characters of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Little Life&lt;/em&gt; is one of those books that, upon completion, you wish to have been a bit more longer - or to have never ended. A book that will forever have a special place on my bookshelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Curry Coast</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/03/27/the-curry-coast/"/>
   <updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/03/27/the-curry-coast</id>
   <content type="html">A travel writer’s greatest challenge is to transport his readers to the realm he is trying to describe with his words, experiencing the same bliss as he did, through his work. Binoo K John, however, had a particularly uphill challenge in convincing me with The Curry Coast, as the subject of the book is my homeland, the Malabar Coast. But when you, as a true Malabari, yearn to rediscover the charm of Calicut, the quaintness of Cannanore and the serenity of Mahe, Binoo can claim success for himself.

Five hundred years after Vasco da Gama discovered the sea-route around the Cape of Good Hope to India, the author embarks on a journey to the Malabar Coast, a land that has long been the bone of contention between various powers, colonial and otherwise. In the intervening centuries, the Malabar coast has transformed itself, reincarnating itself as a melting pot of cultures, traditions and heritage, remnants that various warriors of the past left behind in this battlefield. Binoo rightly starts off at Calicut, the gateway to Malabar, and importantly, where the Portuguese conquistador first set foot and terminates his sojourn in Goa, the last bastion of the Portuguese empire.

Delightfully written and evocative of the essence of Malabar, Binoo’s travelogue is a refreshing Sunday afternoon read.
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Paranoia.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/03/06/paranoia/"/>
   <updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/03/06/paranoia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amidst this insanity,&lt;br /&gt;
There seemed to be some clarity,&lt;br /&gt;
Her presence, although a rarity,&lt;br /&gt;
Was not removed from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am, devoid of brevity,&lt;br /&gt;
For I have lost my sanity,&lt;br /&gt;
Is my heart in captivity,&lt;br /&gt;
Or am I drowning in perplexity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I fall deeper, helplessly&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot stop feeling you, infectiously&lt;br /&gt;
Driving nails into my soul, mercilessly&lt;br /&gt;
Have you not known? I have lost all sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sorceress.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/02/19/sorceress/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/02/19/sorceress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A beloved name lies inside my heart&lt;br /&gt;
A fleeting glance, became the start&lt;br /&gt;
A missing word, is what I awaited&lt;br /&gt;
A wretched deception, was her creation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorceress, she bound me in her spell&lt;br /&gt;
Devoid of resistance, deeper I fell&lt;br /&gt;
Failed to realize, all was a facade&lt;br /&gt;
Boundless love, seethed in my veins.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An Era of Darkness</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/02/17/an-era-of-darkness/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/02/17/an-era-of-darkness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The genesis of &lt;em&gt;An Era of Darkness&lt;/em&gt; is the brilliant speech made by the author at the Oxford Union. At that time, the speech caught the imagination of many Indians, who were fed by English novelists who extolled the greatness of the British Empire, with a few of them even going as far ahead as to lay claim to some of India’s assets now as their ‘gifts’: the Indian railway network is a prime example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been many, excluding British nationalist authors of Niall Ferguson and the like, who have staunchly defended colonialism. The proponents of this argument have often claimed that British colonialism was less evil than those of the other colonial powers (Leopold’s Belgian Congo comes to mind). Often, these arguments are made considering how the commonwealth nations and the United States are faring today in the modern era. But what about a land which was by far the most prosperous nation in the world, the contributor of a quarter of the world’s GDP, the famed home of renowned artisans, acclaimed universities and a locus of science and technology, before the arrival of the East India Company in the 1600s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this argument that Shashi Tharoor deftly brings down in his well-researched book, &lt;em&gt;An Era of Darkness&lt;/em&gt;. Though a claimed nationalist, Tharoor’s arguments are not a biased rebuttal, they are backed by verifiable facts. With every chapter, the author hits home the argument that &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; that the British did in India was never for the Indians, but for its own benefit. The racism, the economic exploitation, the policy of &lt;em&gt;divide et impera&lt;/em&gt; were all meant to subjugate a once great people to their knees, to bow down to the might and ruthlessness of the Empire, to pay for the avarice of the East India Company. Raj apologists may claim that the idea of a unified India did not exist before the British Empire; but who is to say that left to its own, India could not have been a unified, pluralist democracy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However ruthless and criminal the British Empire may be, it represented a democracy with free press and a conscious international image. This was not the case with many colonial powers or dictatorships around the world and Tharoor considers this to be key to Gandhism’s success. For a dictatorship that considered that exterminating Jews was the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; thing, Gandhism and non-violence could have offered them no solutions. In Tharoor’s own words: ‘the ultimate tribute to the British Raj might lie in the quality of the Mahatma who opposed it.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A grim, dark read for anybody, regardless of your interest in colonial history.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Lonely City</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/01/20/the-lonely-city/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/01/20/the-lonely-city</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loneliness is by no means a wholly worthless experience, but rather one that cuts right to the heart of what we value and what we need. Many marvellous things have emerged from the lonely city; things forged in loneliness, but also things that function to redeem it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might not consider myself lonely, but I spend a lot of time alone, in solitude. It’s one of the few things that I am absolutely comfortable with - being comfortable with my own company, travelling alone in my own thoughts. Of course, this does not mean I’m a recluse - I have terrific friends, but I’m much more of an introvert than you might think. I need my own personal space. &lt;em&gt;A lot of personal space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is two things - Olivia Laing’s experiences with loneliness, and a deep study on loneliness in art. She makes a study of people who are alone, who share her loneliness in what is one of the most populous cities on the planet, New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lonely City introduced me to a myriad of artists and photographers, some of them who I have never heard of. Andy Warhol, David Wojnarowicz, Valerie Solanas and Peter Hujar, among others. Laing explores loneliness and solitude in their work, including a brilliant analysis of Edward Hopper’s Nighthawks, on how the painting’s colours and subtle details (some of them which I have never noticed). In Hopper’s own words, &lt;em&gt;‘I was unconsciously painting the loneliness of a large city.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fascinating and poignant, this book is for all the introverts, for the people who are perfectly comfortable in their own company, for those who value their solitude more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Feast of the Goat</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/01/08/feast-of-goats/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/bookmarks/2017/01/08/feast-of-goats</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After reading 52 books in 2016, I thought I’d settle down for a much smaller number this year, mostly because I wanted to delve deeper into the literature I read, spend more time thinking, analyzing, losing myself in the thoughts of the author. The voracious reader in me would still not let go, as I find myself huddled in my room, blazing through book after book. A week into 2017 and I am already into my second read of the year, and boy, it has been a really memorable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to read Latin American fiction, with most of Gabriel García Márquez’s work on my reading list for this year. However, before I step into Márquez’s world of magical realism, I wanted to read another famed Latin American author - Mario Vargas Llosa. His 2000 book, &lt;em&gt;The Feast of the Goat&lt;/em&gt;, is what I got my hands on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Feast of the Goat&lt;/em&gt; is no easy novel to begin with. Llosa vividly portrays the harsh reality of tyranny through the story of the Dominican dictator Rafael Trujillo, ‘the Goat’. The novel, in two parallel threads, follows the last days of the &lt;em&gt;Benevolent Father&lt;/em&gt;, and how his tyrannical rule deprived a fourteen-year old girl, Urania Cabral, of her childhood. A masterful blend of history and fiction, the novel is vivid in it’s depiction of the Dominican Republic under Trujillo’s regime, and often left me gasping for breath, shocked at times as I read Llosa’s prose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a start to 2017 has it been!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On love, and the space between.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/04/love-space-between/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/04/love-space-between</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Romantically, love must surely reside in the gap between desire and fulfilment, in the lack, not the contentment. Love is the ache, the anticipation, the retreat, everything around it but the emotion itself. Which would explain why people get bored of each other, why divorce lawyers just seem to be getting richer and richer and why Ashley Madison does not seem to be a big deal anymore. For we humans have a constant craving to be excited. In this age of instant gratification, where when two people swipe right and you end up on a date, patience has lost its value. Gone are those days when sleepless nights were cherished, when each word that passed through her lips had monumental valie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For love is not contentment - in it can never be content. Love is not fulfilment - it can never be fulfilled. Love is the ache, the incurable want, the never ending desire for someone - that dies when you do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reality, colours and dreams.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/03/reality/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/03/reality</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I once had a painter friend who usually painted scenes from life, mainly deserted rooms, abandoned houses and women. Gradually, his work became more abstract, and his paintings became just rebellious patches of colour. Dark blotches amidst deep shades of blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked about his progress from modern realism to abstraction. Reality has become so untolerable, he said, so bleak, that all I can paint now are the colours of my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colours of my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people get a achance to paint the colours of their dreams? How many people get to dream beyond the visible spectrum and see colours that cannot be hexcoded, cannot be named, yet are just as truly stunning and beautiful like every other colour?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dreams are not blue, they are not as vibrant a riot of colour that put a rangoli to shame. Monochromatic and binary, they exist on the very edge of the spectrum, absorbing as black, reflective as white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In life, seldom are there shades of grey, and what is your life, if nothing but somebody else’s dream?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/08/14/time/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/08/14/time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At any given second, billions of things are happening on Earth. A cloud is forming. An ant colony is carrying out their daily duties. A child is succumbing to hunger. A person is cheating on their spouse. An animal is dying at the hands (or jaws) of something higher up on the food chain. A fish is exploring the Titanic wreckage. A factory is packaging the Oreos you’re going to eat next week. Someone is crying. Someone is falling in love. Millions of people are sending and receiving text messages. All this and so much more is happening simultaneously, but we rarely think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only think about what matters to us, we only think about what we really care about. But, what if you have nothing or nobody to care for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a cannibalistic world, abundant with modern day slaves chasing each other like dogs, does anybody pause and listen to their heartbeat? Listen to what exactly they are feeling at that moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I did. I wish I could go back and act on that impulse when I first had it. I wish I could go back and tell my boss that he is an asshole. I wish I could go back and tell that girl that I’ve fallen for her smile. I wish I could tell my ex that no, she’s the one who’s wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only time could slow down, down to a snail’s pace so that I can feel every microsecond of it. If only life wasn’t about making the quickest decisions in the best possible fashion. If only life gave me a second chance, to go back in time and relive everything that I want to experience now. Maybe then we’d all be more sentient beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe then, things would’ve been better. Maybe then I wouldn’t have to recall her face from a faint memory. Maybe then, I wouldn’t have to keep hearing those painful words rhythmically repeating, like a hollow chant in my head as she broke up with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only time could actually open it’s mouth and tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Metamorphosis.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/07/28/metamorphosis/"/>
   <updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/07/28/metamorphosis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like a moth, I was born in the rain that was her presence. A Kafkaesque metamorphosis, I was transformed into a living being in the cold, soothing rain that spread all over my nascent body. I gyrated to the rhythm of her legs, her anklet a timely metronome. As she looked towards me, I found myself photo taxiing towards her radiance, her light illuminating eveything around us. As her lips parted, I found myself fluttering my wings rapidly in a desperate attempt to defy gravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God, what I wouldn’t do to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I felt like I could do anything. I felt I could fly to close to her brilliance and take it all in. I felt I could spread my wings wide enough and make her light all mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a fallen Icarus, I flew too close to her. My wings shriveled, my body burned. I rapidly descended, my wings a fiery mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, she shone brilliantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fluttering on the ground and awaiting Anubis, I looked up to her. And in that moment, all I could remember was how we had gotten really close, and how every moment felt like I don’t know her at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Two melting snowmen.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/07/05/two-melting-snowmen/"/>
   <updated>2016-07-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/07/05/two-melting-snowmen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Separated by a great white expanse, they stand&lt;br /&gt;
A he and a she, draped in flakes&lt;br /&gt;
Alone they stood, in an unrelenting blizzard&lt;br /&gt;
Forever unknown to each other, in a winter with no end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along came a nomad, armed with a blaze&lt;br /&gt;
Furious sparks spewed from his great light&lt;br /&gt;
The darkness abates and light took it’s place&lt;br /&gt;
And across the abyss, he saw her and was amazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warmed by his gaze she melted away&lt;br /&gt;
Vestiges of her soul moved up his way&lt;br /&gt;
In her warmth his heart did open&lt;br /&gt;
Letting out little birds that fluttered away&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fluid was he, in her warm embrace&lt;br /&gt;
United were they, melting in grace&lt;br /&gt;
And there were no two snowmen when the nomad returned&lt;br /&gt;
But one soul floating away, that He had warmed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Separation.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/06/27/separation/"/>
   <updated>2016-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/06/27/separation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;They said it made the world smaller. They said it made the world come together and connect better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He never felt the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each text he sent, a monotonic increase, each moment he waited, an exponential wait in the aeon. He never felt closer to her, he never felt more connected to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As her smile pleasantly lights up tiny diodes behind his screen, he is amazed. It’s brilliant how these circuits can light up my world, he thinks to himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only he could feel the emotion in those streams of bytes, travelling below the sea and above the ground. If only those binary digits dancing around his screen could morph into Xs and Os. If only the pixels of her hair had the smell of those luscious strands embedded in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe then, his world would become a smaller place.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Incomplete.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/06/27/incomplete/"/>
   <updated>2016-06-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/06/27/incomplete</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a teeming world of people, he was alone. As he walked past the poster that screamed, ‘a small family is a happy family’ and televisions that aired latently erotic advertisements for contraceptives in flashy electronic stores, he couldn’t but smirk. Are there so many of us in the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He scanned the panorama as he waited for the bus. A maddening rush of emotionless people. In a haste to a place they don’t know where, striving to achieve something they know not. A deafeningly silent, perpetually pulsating machine. What are you working for, human? Is money going to complete you? Is your status symbol going to make you whole again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seven and half billion hearts, and none of them could match his rhythm. Fifteen billion eyes, yet none could hold his gaze. Yet, the world says there are too many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For him, the world would always remain incomplete, would forever not have just enough people. For nobody came and held his hand, for nobody came and made his heart skip a beat. His world would forever have a void, a void that nobody else could fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was only one person who could complete him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now he isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A place, somewhere in the sun.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/05/18/sand/"/>
   <updated>2016-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/05/18/sand</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lying on this sand, I let my spirit disappear&lt;br /&gt;
From this world, with just you in tow &lt;br /&gt;
I would let it wander, without pain, forgotten&lt;br /&gt;
To the glorious shelters, somewhere in the sun&lt;br /&gt;
Far away from this world, far away from the pain&lt;br /&gt;
In this glorious sand, I write your name&lt;br /&gt;
I hear the sea sing, I see the clouds spell&lt;br /&gt;
Wandering through the darkness to the light,&lt;br /&gt;
We’d find a place, somewhere in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
