<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Sreeraag Mohan | Personal Webpage</title>
 <link href="http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2017-01-06T12:13:45+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://sreeraagmohan.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Sreeraag Mohan</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>On love, and the space between.</title>
   <link href="http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/thoughts/2016/01/04/test/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/thoughts/2016/01/04/test</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Romantically, love must surely reside in the gap between desire and fulfilment, in the lack, not the contentment. Love is the ache, the anticipation, the retreat, everything around it but the emotion itself. Which would explain why people get bored of each other, why divorce lawyers just seem to be getting richer and richer and why Ashley Madison does not seem to be a big deal anymore. For we humans have a constant craving to be excited. In this age of instant gratification, where when two people swipe right and you end up on a date, patience has lost its value. Gone are those days when sleepless nights were cherished, when each word that passed through her lips had monumental valie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For love is not contentment - in it can never be content. Love is not fulfilment - it can never be fulfilled. Love is the ache, the incurable want, the never ending desire for someone - that dies when you do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reality, colours and dreams.</title>
   <link href="http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/thoughts/2016/01/03/reality/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://sreeraagmohan.github.io/thoughts/2016/01/03/reality</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I once had a painter friend who usually painted scenes from life, mainly deserted rooms, abandoned houses and women. Gradually, his work became more abstract, and his paintings became just rebellious patches of colour. Dark blotches amidst deep shades of blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked about his progress from modern realism to abstraction. Reality has become so untolerable, he said, so bleak, that all I can paint now are the colours of my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colours of my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people get a achance to paint the colours of their dreams? How many people get to dream beyond the visible spectrum and see colours that cannot be hexcoded, cannot be named, yet are just as truly stunning and beautiful like every other colour?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dreams are not blue, they are not as vibrant a riot of colour that put a rangoli to shame. Monochromatic and binary, they exist on the very edge of the spectrum, absorbing as black, reflective as white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In life, seldom are there shades of grey, and what is your life, if nothing but somebody else’s dream?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
